Honghao (Hao) Zhang

honghaoz.com github.com/honghaoz linkedin.com/in/honghaozhang

honghao.zhang@uwaterloo.ca

SUMMARY

Experienced and extremely passionate in iOS development, interested in backend/server and web development. Have more than 5 years' experience of programming and 2 years' experience of software engineering. Constantly striving to learn new technologies and making applications with intuitive and concise UI. Fascinated with new technologies, such as Swift and Adaptive-Layout in iOS development

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Programming Language:

- Proficient: Swift, Objective-C, C/C++, Python
- Familiar: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Java, SQL, Racket, Bash

Software Engineering: Node.js, Git, Jira, Heroku, Parse, Django, Google App Engine, RESTful web service Fluent in Chinese, basic knowledge of Japanese

WORK EXPERIENCES

theScore Inc., Toronto - iOS Engineer (Full-time)

Jun 2015 - Present

- · Responsible for design update for iOS8 and native resolution support for iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus
- Created constraint-based views, such as accessory keyboard for editor, used Auto Layout and Core Graphics
- Refactored the project, wrote unit tests and participated in code reviews to ensure code quality, 478 commits

DogSync, Toronto - iOS Developer (Part-time)

Jan 2015 - Apr 2015

- · Acted as lead developer for front-end implementation, collaborated directly with the designer
- · Responsible for implementation of all views and view controllers, used Adaptive Layout (constraint-based)
- Written in Swift language, focused on component-based implementation and reusable code libraries

Wattpad Inc., Toronto - iOS Developer (Intern)

Aug 2014 - Dec 2014

- Responsible for design update for iOS8 and native resolution support for iPhone 6 and iPhone 6 Plus
- · Created constraint-based views, such as accessory keyboard for editor, used Auto Layout and Core Graphics
- Refactored the project, wrote unit tests and participated in code reviews to ensure code quality

PROJECTS & RESEARCH

2048X - 2048 with AI solver (iOS, Swift) Team Lead

Feb 2015 - Apr 2015

- iOS app written purely in Swift. Fully functional game with Retro design
- Solve 2048 game with 4 different AI (Artificial Intelligence) algorithms
- · Submitted in App Store, 85 paid installations

UW Info Session App (iOS, Objective-C, Python, GAE, Parse) Individual Feb 2014 - May 2014

- · Mobile app for querying info sessions held in University of Waterloo, set reminders and search by program
- · Implemented backend service and designed beautiful UWaterloo style UI independently
- Submitted in App Store, 11 released versions, more than 830 installations and nearly 891 API requests per day

Open Source Tools/Libraries (Swift, Objective-C, C)

Jan 2014 - Present

- Ji (軟) 🗗 an XML/HTML parser for Swift. 386 stars on Github.com
- Loggerithm 🗗 a lightweight Swift logger with elegant colorful login messages. 216 stars on Github.com
- Demo for self-resizing UICollectionViewCell with Auto Layout 🗗 Dynamic Cell views. 89 stars on Github.com

Individual iOS Apps (iOS, Swift, Objective-C)

June 2014 - Present

- <u>Date Formatter</u> ♂ developer tool for verifying ISO 8601 date format with references. Submitted in App Store
- Tap Tap Heart Rate 🗗 mobile application for measuring heart rate, focus on UI design. 1.55k installations

UWaterloo Course Notifier (Python, HTML5, CSS3, GAE) Individual Dec 2013 - Jan 2014

- · Web app for querying updated course schedules and setting email alerts for course openings
- Developed database system and designed easy-to-use webpages with clear and consistent UI
- Helped nearly 45 students successfully enroll in their desired courses each term

IEEE Standard MicroMouse Maze Competition (C) <u>Team Leader</u>

May 2011 - Jun 2011

- Created the maze search system and implemented 'Shielding Dead End' algorithm
- Won 1st place in the competition with perfect algorithm and excellent hardware regulation

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Waterloo, Canada

· Master of Engineering, Major in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Sep 2013 - Jun 2015

Concentration in Software Engineering

- Cumulative GPA: 88.75/100
- · Relevant Courses: Algorithm Design and Analysis; Foundations of Software Engineering;

Software Design and Architectures; Software Testing, Quality Assurance and Maintenance, Database Systems; Distributed System; Data Structures and Data Management;

Designing Functional Programs (Scheme); Elementary Algorithm Design and Data Abstraction (C)

Southeast University

Nanjing, China

• Bachelor of Engineering Degree, Major in Electrical Engineering & Its Automation Sep 2008 - Jun 2012

Cumulative GPA: 84.0/100

• Relevant Courses: Programming and Algorithmic Language (C++), Comprehensive of Computer (C/C++)

Basic of Computer Software Technique, Introduction to Information Communication Network

Professional Development

Udacity (Online Course)

• Intro to Algorithms (certificated) Nov 2014 - Present

• Web Development (certificated) Nov - Dec 2013

Introduction to Computer Science (Python) (certificated)

Jul - Nov 2013

• Introduction to Programming (Java) (certificated) Oct 2013 - Jan 2014

Coursera (Online Course)

Algorithms: Design and Analysis, Part 1 (certificated)

Jun - Jul 2014

Computer Networks (University of Washington) (certificated)
 Jan - Apr 2014

ACTIVITIES

Volunteer of '2010 Xiao Hongxin' community activities **Group Leader**

Jul 2010

- · Planed and organized Community Safety Lectures and advocating low-carbon life in community
- Led the group that won the 'Summer Social Practice Excellent Team of Southeast University" title

Monitor of Class 160083 of Electrical Engineering Department Aug 2009 - Jun 2010

- Led the class that won the first prize in the 2009 'Singing for the Motherland' Competition of SEU
- Organized the 2010 EE School Recreational Sports Meeting successfully. Planed a series of class activities.

HONORS & AWARDS

16287 Alumni Scholarship of EE School	Jun 2011
Individual Scholarship of Innovative Practice	Mar 2010
Individual Scholarship of C++ programming (two semesters)	Sep 2009
First Prize of 4th IEEE Standard MicroMouse Maze Competition of Southeast University	May 2011
Third Prize of 2010 Physical Competition of Southeast University	Sep 2010
Third Prize of 2 nd Energy Saving and Emission Reduction Innovation Competition	Apr 2010
First Prize of Web Page Design Competition of Electrical Engineering Department	May 2009